worldfootprints.com 2017-07-05

# Privacy Policy | World Footprints

## WorldFootprints.com Privacy Policy

WorldFootprints.com values the users of our web site (the "Web Site") and the products and services offered on it (the "WorldFootprints.com Products and Services"). We recognize that you may be concerned about our collection, use, and disclosure of your personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that we may collect when you use the Web Site and the WorldFootprints.com Products and Services. Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have implemented this Privacy Policy to inform you of the information that we collect from you, how we collect this information, and what we do with it after we collect it. By using the WorldFootprints.com Web Site you are accepting the practices described in this policy. If you have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: [privacy@WorldFootprints.com](mailto:privacy@WorldFootprints.com).

## Does WorldFootprints.com Ever Make Changes to its Privacy Policy?

We may make changes to the Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by sending you an email (if you are a Vendor), posting a notice on the home page of the Web Site, or, through the use of cookies, informing you when you first sign on to the Web Site after we have made changes. If you receive notification of a change in our Privacy Policy, you must review the new Privacy Policy carefully to make sure you understand our practices and procedures. You will not be able to receive notices from us if your cookies are not set to accept.

## What Types of Information Does WorldFootprints.com Collect From Me?

**Personal Information** \- We collect Personal Information from you. As explained above, Personal Information is information that can be used to identify you individually, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, credit card number, and financial information. **Non-Personal Information** \- We also collect "non-personal" information from you, such as your browser type, the URL of the previous web site you visited, your ISP, operating system, and your IP Address. This information ("Non-Personal Information") cannot be easily used to personally identify you.

## How and When Does WorldFootprints.com Collect This Information?

**Providing Information to Us** \- We collect Personal Information from you when you provide it to us. For example, if you purchase a product sold through a Shop, we may collect your name, mailing address, telephone number, credit card number, and email address. If you create a Vendor Account, we may collect your name, tax identification number, mailing address, email address, and other information that we request in the registration process. If you sign up to receive a newsletter, we will collect your email address. **Communications With Us** \- If you communicate with us regarding the Web Site or the WorldFootprints.com Services, we will collect any information that you provide to us in any such communication. **Analytic and Reporting Technologies** \- Like the operators of most web sites, we use analytic and reporting technologies to record Non-Personal Information such as Internet domain and host names, Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser software and operating system types, clickstream patterns, and the dates and times that the Web Site and the WorldFootprints.com Services are accessed.

## How Does WorldFootprints.com Use My Information?

**Personal Information** \- We use Personal Information primarily for our own internal purposes, such as providing, maintaining, evaluating, and improving the WorldFootprints.com Services and the Web Site, fulfilling requests for information, producing and shipping the products that you order, and providing customer support. For example, if you create a Vendor Account, we will use the information that you provide to communicate with you and pay you any commissions that you earn. Similarly, if you sign up to receive a WorldFootprints.com newsletter, we will use the email address you provide to send you the newsletters. **Non-Personal Information** \- We use non-personal information to track your use of the Web Site and the WorldFootprints.com Services and for other internal purposes, particularly providing, maintaining, evaluating, and improving the WorldFootprints.com Services and the Web Site.

## When Will WorldFootprints.com Disclose My Information to Third Parties?

Generally speaking, we do not intentionally disclose your information to third parties without your consent. However we reserve the right to do so because it is necessary to the operation and continued growth of our business or to protect the rights of others. These instances are discussed below: **Disclosure to Successors** \- We may disclose your Personal Information to any successor-in-interest of ours, such as a company that acquires us. In the event WorldFootprints.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or by a notice on our Web Site of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. **Disclosure to Unaffiliated Third Parties** \- We may disclose your Personal Information to prevent an emergency, to protect or enforce our rights, to protect or enforce the rights of a third party, or as required or permitted by law (including, without limitation, to comply with a subpoena or court order). In particular, if you are a Vendor, we may disclose your information to a third party that alleges that you have infringed their intellectual property rights through the products sold through your Shop. Similarly, if you allege that a Vendor allegedly infringes your intellectual property rights, we may disclose your information to that Vendor. **Disclosure to Third-Party Service Providers** \- We may contract with various third parties who help us provide and maintain the Web Site or the WorldFootprints.com Services. For example, we use a third-party to process payments made to us, and may subcontract out production, fulfillment, or other operations. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to prevent such third parties from disclosing your Personal Information, except for the purpose of providing the services in question. We cannot guarantee that such third parties will not disclose your Personal Information. **Disclosure to Vendors** \- If you purchase a product from a Shop, WorldFootprints.com may provide your name, and the city and state information provided by you to the Vendor. In the Vendor Agreement, WorldFootprints.com contractually obligates each Vendor not to use or disclose this information for any purposes other than internal record keeping, and for marketing their Shops, only if you have opted in to receive marketing material directly from the Vendor. We cannot guarantee all Vendors will comply with this obligation. **Disclosure of Non-Personal Information** \- We will disclose Non-Personal Information, in aggregate form, to potential strategic partners, advertisers, investors, customers, and others. You may not "opt out" of the sharing of this information. However, it cannot be easily used to identify you personally.

## What About Cookies?

A cookie is a message that is sent to your computer from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Most web sites use cookies. We use cookies to track your use of the Web Site and the WorldFootprints.com Services, provide you with a more personalized user experience, and to allow you to sign in and begin use of the WorldFootprints.com Services automatically when you visit the Web Site. We may also use cookies to ensure that you have been notified of and agreed to the then-current version of the Terms of Service, Privacy Policy, and any other agreements and policies relating to your use of the Web Site or the WorldFootprints.com Services. Cookies used by WorldFootprints.com are not linked to Personal Information.Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by WorldFootprints.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

## Does WorldFootprints.com Protect My Personal Information?

**Personal Information** \- Whenever we obtain your Personal Information, we use commercially reasonable efforts to protect it from unauthorized access or disclosure. However, we are not insurers of the security of your Personal Information. Accordingly, we assume no liability for any disclosure of data due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third party access or other acts of third parties, or acts or omissions beyond our reasonable control. **Web Site Content** \- The content that you store, post, or transmit on or through the Web Site, such as message board postings, "About Me" pages, and images on your Products, may be accessed by other users, including people that you do not know. We are not responsible for the actions of others. Therefore, you should use care in communicating with other users and only disclose your Personal Information to other users that you know to be trustworthy. You should not assume that your content will be kept private.

## How Can I Review and Make Changes to My Personal Information?

You can obtain a copy of and request that we correct errors in your Personal Information by emailing us at [privacy@WorldFootprints.com](mailto:privacy@WorldFootprints.com). For your protection, you will be required to provide proof of your identity to obtain a copy of your Personal Information. If your Personal Information changes or if you no longer want to use the WorldFootprints.com Services, you may correct, update or deactivate your Personal Information and/or your account through your account management screen. If you would like to deactivate or terminate your account you can also contact Customer Service.

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as a credit card number and/or social security number on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## Does This Privacy Policy Apply When I Access Third Party Web Sites?

You may be able to access third-party web sites directly from the Web Site. This Privacy Policy does not apply when you access such web sites. We cannot control how third parties may use Personal Information you disclose to them, so you should carefully review the privacy policy of any third-party web site you visit before using it or disclosing your Personal Information to its provider.

## What About Children's Privacy?

**Under Thirteen** \- The WorldFootprints.com Services are intended for users ages 13 and older. Accordingly, we will not knowingly collect or use any Personal Information from children that we know to be under the age of 13. In addition, we will delete any information in our database that we know originates from a child under the age of 13. **Thirteen to Seventeen** \- Prospective users between the ages of 13 and 17 can only use the WorldFootprints.com Services under their parents' or legal guardian's supervision. If you are between the ages of 13 and 17, you, your parent, or your legal guardian may request that we delete any of your Personal Information in our database and/or opt-out from receiving communications from us. If you wish to do so, please contact us at the email address provided below.

## Can I "Opt Out" From Receiving Communications From WorldFootprints.com?

We provide you the opportunity to opt-out of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [privacy@WorldFootprints.com](mailto:privacy@WorldFootprints.com). We also offer you an opportunity to opt-out of certain communications through your account management screen. If you need assistance you may contact us at [privacy@WorldFootprints.com](mailto:privacy@WorldFootprints.com); or via mail sent to 8639-B 16th Street, #201, Silver Spring, MD 20910.You will be notified when your Personal Information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.
